在前面的故事里…
Previously on "Transformers Prime"...
有一名霸天虎受到擎天柱的尊敬
There is one who Prime seems to respect.
骇翼 你有另一个选择
Dreadwing, there is another path.
你这样喋喋不休有意义吗 擎天柱？
Is there a point to your bluster, Prime?
尽管下载到的铁堡数据不完整
The download of the Iacon database may have been incomplete
但我们已经拥有了战舰所破译的四个坐标
but we now possess four sets of coordinates decoded by the ship.
如果我们想赶在霸天虎之前得到铁堡的遗物
If we are to have any hope of recovering the Iacon relics before the Decepticons do
我们就必须分头行动
we must divide our resources.
但是擎天柱
But, Optimus
我们人手本来就不足…
when it comes to numbers, we are already at a grave disadvantage.
派出多支小队
Dispatching multiple squadrons will enable us to pursue all four coordinates simultaneously.
同时开始定位另外三组坐标
Triangulate coordinates of the other three relics.
这是一场我们输不起的竞赛
This is one race that we absolutely cannot afford to lose.
坐标显示第二个铁堡遗物位于
The coordinates indicate that the second of these four Iacon relics
这个世界的最底端
lies at the very bottom of this world.
为了贯彻您的意志
I will journey to the ends of this or any world
我愿意前往任何世界的尽头 威震天陛下
to serve your will, lord Megatron.
那就带着我的战利品回来 骇翼！
Then return with my prize, Dreadwing.
向我证明 作为一个副官
and prove you are more worthy of being my second-in-command
你比你的前任更加称职
than those who have preceded you.
指数仪 十字钳 激光手术刀
Inner stat, cross clamp, laser scalpel
钻头 还有一个轻微损伤的变形齿轮
durabyllium drill, and one slightly damaged but operational T-cog.
来自我那狡诈的克隆体
courtesy of my traitorous clone...
能够将我完全修复的设备一应俱全
everything I require to make myself whole.
只是一个简单 无痛的手术
A simple, painless procedure.
真的没什么
Nothing to it, really.
只要有勇气
Provided one possesses the nerve.
嗯？
Hmm?
四支霸天虎分队同时经过环陆桥前往四个不同地点？
Four detachments of Decepticons Ground Bridging to four different continents at the exact same time?
啊…手术推迟！
Ah. Procedure postponed.
小心行事 隔板
Be on your guard, Bulkhead.
拉斐尔 锁定其余坐标
Raphael, lock on to the remaining coordinates.
我将前往南极
I will embark for the Antarctic.
至于你 我的老朋友
As for you, old friend
我想让一个人陪同你执行任务
I would prefer that you have company on your mission.
没有人能跟我同行了 擎天柱
No one is left to join me, Optimus.
即便福勒探员恢复意识
Even if Agent Fowler were alert...
嗯…在说我什么？
Em? Who's talking about me?
他也不过是个人类
He's human.
这个星球上还有一个汽车人 我想他是最终人选
I was considering the only remaining Autobot alternative on this planet.
等等 你不是认真的吧！
But, you... you can't be serious!
千斤顶桀骜不驯 粗俗无礼
Wheeljack is insubordinate, a ruffian.
更何况 他是隔板的搭档
Besides, he's Bulkhead's partner.
你的专长是科技
Your expertise is scientific
而千斤顶是个强大的战士
but Wheeljack is a highly capable warrior.
由他暂时陪同对你有好处
You would be wise to welcome the temporary alliance.
啊 操作环陆桥的遥控器
Ah, a remote control for the Ground Bridge.
我爱霸天虎的科学家
I love Decepticon scientists.
呃…我讨厌这个星球！
I despise this planet.
不是灼热的沙漠
If it isn't a scorching desert
就是寒冷的不毛之地！
it is a frigid wasteland.
好了 我的霸天虎兄弟们你们在哪儿？
Now, where are you, my Decepticon brethren?
啊！快跑啊 你这悲催的蠢玩意儿！
Faster, you pathetic excuse for transportation!
霸天虎！知道你们打下了自己的战舰指挥官吗？
Decepticons, do you not realize you have just shot down your ship's Commander?!
啊！
Aah!
你指挥不了任何人 叛徒！
You command no one, deserter.
天震？但是 你已经…！
Skyquake? B-but you're...
你把我和我兄弟搞混了
You mistake me for my brother
他已经与火种源同在了
who is one with the Allspark
你最清楚他怎么死的 前任指挥官 红蜘蛛…
as you are, no doubt, aware, former commander Starscream.
啊…哈…哈哈哈
Ahhh... Hahaha...
要是我能做得了主
Were it up to me
我立马就会在这里把你了结
I would end this here and now.
但是作为威震天陛下的副官
But it is my duty as first lieutenant to Megatron
将叛徒带给我的主人进行公正的审判
to render all traitors to my lord and master
是我的职责
for due punishment.
副官？
First lieutenant?!
那是我的官位！
That's my post!
呃 曾经 是我的
Uh, was my post.
骇翼指挥官
Commander Dreadwing
威震天会派他的副手来 一定是一项十分重要的任务
this must be a very important mission if Megatron has dispatched his second-in-command.
是搜寻能量 还是其他的什么事？
Scouting for Energon, or something else altogether?
与你无关
That is none of your concern.
要是告诉我你在找什么
If I knew what you were looking for
或许我能提供帮助
perhaps I could help.
我们已经到达了坐标地点
We have arrived at the coordinates.
遗物 已经被带走了！
The relic. It has been taken.
遗物？什么遗物？
Relic? What sort of relic?
搜索附近区域！
Search the area!
骇翼指挥官
Commander Dreadwing
发现车辆的痕迹
we have discovered vehicle tracks.
汽车人！
The Autobots.
虽然有可能 但我从来不知道
Perhaps. Though I've never known them to plant flags
他们还会留下旗帜夸示胜利
at the site of their victories.
别挑战我的耐性 叛徒！
Do not try me, traitor.
我会把你抛尸在这片冻原上
I will leave your lifeless husk in this frozen waste.
你们两个 看着囚犯
You two, guard the prisoner.
擎天柱 我只说一次 交出遗物！
Optimus Prime, I will request only once that you surrender the relic.
我把这话还给你 骇翼
I was going to request the same of you, Dreadwing.
那看来我们在同一起跑线上
Then I would say that we are on equal footing
只不过 我们是五对一
were it not that there are five of us and only one of you.
是六 要是你给我解开这荒唐的手铐
Six, if you'd relieve me of these ridiculous manacles.
你的准头真差
Your aim is poor.
只是目标不同罢了！
That is a matter of perspective.
不！
No!
这样僵持下去我们能…怎么样？
A stalemate would leave us where?
骇翼指挥官！
Commander Dreadwing!
我们配合真默契！
What a team we make!
我很高兴你能获胜 擎天柱！
I am so glad that you prevailed, Optimus Prime!
那个可恶的骇翼差点杀了我！
That wretch Dreadwing was going to terminate me.
好了 只要你给我解开手铐
Now, if you could just remove my bonds
我就带你去遗物那里
I can lead you straight to the relic.
不解开你也得带我去
You will lead me there regardless.
哼 不客气…
Hmph. You're welcome.
讲点道理 擎天柱！
Be reasonable, Prime!
严寒会把我们的促动器都冻住的！
This cold will freeze both our actuators.
这里的温度很低 但不足以影响到我们的生理构造
The current temperatures are not extreme enough to affect our biology.
你不会有事的
You'll be fine.
没事 却不好过！
Fine but miserable.
真没想到 我为汽车人做了那么多
And I cannot believe that you take our alliances for granted.
你却毫不领情！
After all I have done for the Autobots...
帮助你恢复记忆
helping to restore your memory
救了阿尔茜一命
saving Arcee's life.
你偶尔向我们提供帮助
While you have at times proved beneficial to us
只不过是为了你自己的利益
it has been only to further your own interests.
好吧 但我们不可能都像你那样无私 不是吗？
Well, we can't all be as selfless as you, now, can we?
啊哈！如我所料
Aha, as I suspected...
人类…遗物肯定在这里
humans. We will find the relic here.
让我们夺回本属于我们的东西吧 啊！
So, let us reclaim what is rightfully ours. Aah!
我们不能就这样冲进一个人类设施\N去搜索塞博特恩的圣物
We cannot simply enter a human facility to search for Cybertronian relics.
哪怕是他们偷走的 也不行？
Not even if they stole it?
我也不能让无辜的人类面对一个危险的霸天虎！
Nor can I expose innocent humans to a dangerous Decepticon.
拉斐尔 福勒探员恢复知觉了吗？
Rafael, has Agent Fowler regained consciousness?
我在这儿 擎天柱 你那边是什么情况？
I'm here, Prime. What's your situation?
我需要进入一处考察站 就在我所在的位置
I require access to a research facility at my current coordinates.
让我联系一下
Let me make a call.
我们就这么干等着挨冻？
Are we really going to wait out here in the freezing cold
完全被人类官僚驱使？
completely at the mercy of human bureaucracy?!
基地已经清空了 擎天柱 尽量不要破坏设施
Base is clear, Prime. Try not to wreck the joint.
十分感谢 福勒探员
Many thanks, Agent Fowler.
遗物仍被封在冰中
The relic remained sealed in the ice.
虽然早知道你毫无羞耻之心 红蜘蛛
I knew you were of questionable honor, Starscream
但你竟然投靠汽车人
but aiding the Autobots
这是我容忍的极限了
that is a capital offense.
什么？
What?!
但是我 我特意给你留下了记号！
But I... I left tracks for you on purpose!
好让你来营救我！
so you could rescue me from my captor.
骇翼 我不会让你带走遗物的
Dreadwing, I cannot allow you to leave here with this relic.
我知道 擎天柱
I know that, Prime
但我不打算给你选择的余地！
but I do not intend to give you a choice.
如此兴师动众 这遗物必定非同凡响！
Given all the fuss, this relic must be truly special.
一件护甲 出自霸天虎之手
Armor... of Decepticon origin.
精锐护甲…
The Apex armor.
十分合身！
A perfect fit.
你竟敢染指本属于威震天陛下的东西？
You dare to claim that which rightfully belongs to Lord Megatron?
你能奈我何 指挥官？
And what do you intend to do about it, Commander?
现在你看起来没那么高大强壮了 不是吗？
Not so big and strong now, are you?
自从上次在飞过山身上打个洞以来 我还从没这么高兴过！
I haven't had this much fun since I punched that hole in Cliffjumper.
让我送你去见你心爱的双胞胎兄弟吧
Allow me to reunite you with your beloved twin.
而你 擎天柱
And you, Optimus Prime.
我要把你的火种活生生地敲出来
I will beat the living Spark out of you
这样我就不用再忍受你那装模作样的态度了！
just so I never again have to endure your pontificating.
骇翼 我们的战斗还未结束
Dreadwing, our battle remains unfinished
但如果我们不团结起来对付我们共同的敌人…
but if we do not unite against our common foe...
红蜘蛛会把我们都干掉
Starscream will destroy us both.
我去吸引他注意力
I will draw his attention.
力气大不怕你会飞！
Might beats flight.
你才该魂归火种源！
You shall be the one to join with the Allspark.
像挠痒痒一样 哈哈哈 蠢货们！
That tickled! Ahhhahaha... Fools!
本座现在不光是英明 而且神武！
Not only am I intelligent, I am invincible!
但是你不能飞！
Yet you cannot fly.
没有人是完美的
Nobody's perfect.
好了 告诉我另外三个遗物
Now, tell me of the other three relics.
是不是也像我这件闪亮的新装甲一样威力无穷？
Are they as powerful as my shiny new armor?
正是为了避免像你这样的人染指
They were hidden away precisely to keep them from the hands of those like you.
他的威力太强大了 擎天柱！后退！
He is far too powerful, Prime! Fall back!
懦夫
Cowards.
你们休想逃出我的掌心！
You will not escape my might.
等等
Wait.
你们想算计我？
You two are up to something.
现在 我们联手的目的已经达到了
Now that our alliance has served its purpose...
精锐护甲随着红蜘蛛一起消失了
Starscream is gone and the Apex armor with him.
没有了目标 还有必要继续打下去吗？
Is there really a need to renew battle when the goal has been lost?
我们还有别的账要算…
We have other unfinished matters.
我对天震没有恶意
I bore Skyquake no malice
我导致了他的死亡 我也很遗憾
and I regret the role I played in his demise
所以我也向你提出相同的请求
so I will appeal to you as I once did your twin...
离开霸天虎势力
turn your back on the Decepticon cause
协助我结束这场战争
and help me end this war.
为了你兄弟和所有牺牲的战士
For his sake, and for all who have fallen.
今天你救了我一命
You saved my life today.
下次见面我再杀你！
I will terminate you the next time we meet.
如此也罢 骇翼
So be it, Dreadwing.